<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Portfolio - Preston Locke</title>
    <link>https://prestonlocke.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Portfolio - Preston Locke</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 10:01:29 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://prestonlocke.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chess</title>
      <link>https://prestonlocke.net/projects/personal/chess/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 08:09:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prestonlocke.net/projects/personal/chess/</guid>
      <description>This project has been years in the making&amp;hellip; I first learned chess in middle school, right around the same time that I started visiting my local library in search of programming knowledge (I didn&amp;rsquo;t have internet at home and my school never offered a single CS class until the year after I graduated high school). Because I grew to greatly enjoy playing chess with my friends, I thought it would be really cool to make my own implementation of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Password Manager</title>
      <link>https://prestonlocke.net/projects/collaborations/password-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 13:23:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prestonlocke.net/projects/collaborations/password-manager/</guid>
      <description>A partner and I created this application for our Computer Security and Privacy course as our final project. The goal was to implement a basic password manager that could properly encrypt/decrypt information, as well as provide feedback to the user about the strength of each password. I implemented most of the functionality, including data storage and encryption, as well as the optimized algorithm for checking passwords against pre-existing dictionaries of insecure passwords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QNotPad</title>
      <link>https://prestonlocke.net/projects/personal/qnotpad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 16:06:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prestonlocke.net/projects/personal/qnotpad/</guid>
      <description>This project was inspired by the classic Notepad application on Windows. I used this opportunity to learn how to use the Qt framework, but this was also my first native (non-web) project that included a graphical user interface. Previously I had only written code that printed output to the terminal, which is why I chose to copy the design of a pre-existing application rather than create my own design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CPUID</title>
      <link>https://prestonlocke.net/projects/personal/cpuid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 15:50:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prestonlocke.net/projects/personal/cpuid/</guid>
      <description>I started this project after becoming curious how hardware detection tools like CPU-Z work. When I looked up the developers of the software, CPUID, I learned that their namesake was also the name of an Assembly instruction that returns info about a machine&amp;rsquo;s CPU! Since my Computer Systems Organization class taught me about the inner workings of a processor and how Assembly code works, I really wanted to see if I could write my own code to utilize the CPUID instruction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A* Algorithm Visualization</title>
      <link>https://prestonlocke.net/projects/collaborations/a-star-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 11:27:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prestonlocke.net/projects/collaborations/a-star-visualization/</guid>
      <description>This project used the PyGame library for Python. Myself and two other classmates collaborated over the last month of our Algorithms course to create this visualization as our final project. I mainly worked on the user interface because I was able to quickly learn how to use PyGame to create the cells and the UI control elements, as well as the main event loop for the program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PotLuck</title>
      <link>https://prestonlocke.net/projects/collaborations/potluck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 11:17:57 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://prestonlocke.net/projects/collaborations/potluck/</guid>
      <description>PotLuck is a cross-platform mobile application that helps people find recipes based on the ingredients they already have. You can cook alone or with friends, and the app allows you to pool together your group&amp;rsquo;s available ingredients. By removing the guesswork out of knowing what what&amp;rsquo;s needed vs what you already have, PotLuck makes it easy to decide what to cook.
The app was implemented using Flutter for the UI and Firebase for the user authentication, data storage (Cloud Firestore), and recipe search backend (Cloud Functions/Node.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
